Frederik Pohl Papers
Frederik Pohl Papers
1917-1969
Pohl, Frederik, 1919-
11.25 linear ft.
Correspondence (1934-1968); manuscripts by Pohl and others (1947-1965); legal and financial papers (1917-1964); and published material. Correspondents include Forrest J Ackerman, Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, Judith Merril, Clifford Simak, many others. Collection also includes a large selection of fanzines and convention material.
149523
Biographical History
Frederik George Pohl, Jr. (1919-2013) was an American science fiction writer, editor, publisher, and agent.
Born on 26 November 1919 in Queens, New York, the son of Frederik G. and. Anna J. (Mason) Pohl, he attended public schools in Brooklyn and was otherwise self-educated. In 1938 he became a charter member, with Cyril Kornbluth and others, of Isaac Asimov's Futurian Literary Society, founded in Brooklyn. From 1939 to 1943 he was the first editor of Astounding Stories and Super Science Stories.
After serving with the U. S. Army Air Force during World War II he briefly worked as an advertising copywriter in New York, but he soon resumed his career in publishing. At Popular Science between 1946 and 1949 he was an editor in the book department and the assistant circulation manager. From 1946-1953 he was also a literary agent for many of the leading science fiction writers of the period, including Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, and Robert Heinlein. By 1953 he had decided to devote himself full time to writing and continued as a freelance writer in science fiction until 1960.
From 1959-1969 Pohl worked at Galaxy Publishing Corporation as editor of Galaxy Science Fiction, If, Magabook, and World of Tomorrow. In 1971 and 1972 he was executive editor of Ace Books in New York, and in 1973 he became science fiction editor at Bantam Books. In the mid-1970s he returned to writing; his best-known work from this period is his Heechee series, the first of which (Gateway) won both the Nebula and the Hugo for best novel. He was a frequent guest on Long John Nebel's radio show from the 1950s to the early 1970s, and an international lecturer.
He served as president of the Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA) from 1974 to 1976. He served on the jury for the Theodore Sturgeon Memorial Award from 1995-2013, and presented numerous lectures at the Center for the Study of Science Fiction (University of Kansas)
His awards include four Hugos, three Nebulas, the National Book Award (1980), the Damon Knight Memorial Grand Master Award (1993), and the J. W. Eaton Lifetime Achievement Award in Science Fiction (2009). In 1998 he was inducted into the Science Fiction and Fantasy Hall of Fame.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frederik Pohl Papers consists of correspondence, legal and financial material, writings in manuscript form, and miscellaneous material. Included at the end is Pohl's collection of fanzines and convention material.
Correspondence constitutes the largest part of the papers. Science fiction authors represented in the papers by a more than twenty-year span of correspondence include Forrest J Ackerman, Isaac Asimov, James Blish, Ray Bradbury, L. Sprague DeCamp, Lester Del Rey, Robert Heinlein, Damon Knight, Cyril Kornbluth, David Kyle, Willy Ley, Judith Merril, Clifford Simak, E.E. (Doc) Smith, Wilson Tucker, Jack Williamson, Richard Wilson, and Donald Wollheim. Other notable correspondents are Poul Anderson, Alfred Bester, Algis Budrys, John Beynon Harris, Keith Laumer, Fritz Leiber, Robert Silverberg, and Theodore Sturgeon.
Correspondents are sometimes identified on the letters by initials, nicknames, or coded signatures. A list of these initials - along with some pseudonyms - follows.
BB
Betty Ballantine
CK
Cyril Kornbluth (Cyril Judd, when writing with Judith Merril)
DK
Damon Knight
DL
Dorothy Lessing
FJA
Forrest J Ackerman
FL
Fritz Leiber
FP
Frederik Pohl
IA
Isaac Asimov
IB
Ian Ballantine
JB
James Blish
JBH
John Beynon Harris (John Wyndham)
JL
Jacques Lacroix-Harcourt
KL
Keith Laumer
PK
Philip Klass (William Tenn)
RAH
Robert A. Heinlein (Lyle Monroe)
RL
Robert Lowndes (also Lavond, Dirk, Doc, AE)
RW
Rosalind Wylie
WS
Wallace Stevens (possibly Robert W. Lowndes)
There are also some date abbreviations/pseudonyms: Ghour = September, Agh 3 = 1937
Also prominently represented are agents, publishers, illustrators, and members of the Pohl family. A folder of letters exchanged with unidentified correspondents is located at the end of the alphabetical sequence.
Legal and financial material relates mostly to Frederik Pohl's careers as writer, editor, and agent. Included here are contracts and memoranda of agreement with publishers, as well as general business papers and personal legal files.
Writings contains manuscripts and miscellaneous material by Pohl and other. This include manuscripts of three novelettes and four short stories by Frederik Pohl. There are also manuscripts of short stories by Isaac Asimov, as well as story outlines and proposals by James Bl1sh, Fritz Leiber, Fletcher Pratt, and Dirk Wylie.
A small section of Miscellanea relating to Frederik Pohl, the contents of which are itemized in the shelf list, completes the collection. There are tear sheets of stories written by his clients, newspaper clippings, advertising that he designed, photographs, and other memorabilia.
Filed at the end of the collection are Fanzines, conference material, other fan publications. The bulk are amateur fan publications, known as fanzines; other types of material include bibliographies, indexes, fan organization newsletters, and conference reports and proceedings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, and chronologically within each folder. Legal and financial material is arranged alphabetically by type. Writings are arranged alphabetically by author. Miscellaneous is arranged alphabetically by type. Fanzines, conference material, other fan publications are arranged alphabetically by title.
Separated Material
Fanzine collection, comprising 8 linear ft., has been transferred to cataloging and integrated with the science fiction periodicals.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science fiction; Radicalism; Literature -- American Fiction; Ackerman, Forrest J.; Aldiss, Brian W. (Brian Wilson), 1925-2017.; Anderson, Poul, 1926-2001.; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992.; Ballantine, Betty.; Ballantine, Ian.; Bester, Alfred.; Bixby, Jerome, 1923-1998.; Blish, James.; Bok, Hannes, 1914-1964.; Boucher, Anthony, 1911-1968.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-2012.; Brunner, John, 1934-1995.; Budrys, Algis, 1931-2008.; Busby, F. M.; Campbell, John W., Jr. (John Wood), 1910-1971.; Carnell, Edward John, 1919-1967.; Davidson, Avram.; De Camp, L. Sprague (Lyon Sprague), 1907-2000.; Del Rey, Lester, 1915-1993.; Dick, Philip K.; Dickson, Gordon R.; Disch, Thomas M.; Ellison, Harlan.; Farmer, Philip José.; Galouye, Daniel F.; Greenberg, Martin, 1918-; Harrison, Harry, 1925-2012.; Heinlein, Robert A. (Robert Anson), 1907-1988.; Herbert, Frank.; Jenkins, Will, 1896-1975.; Kauffmann, Stanley, 1916-; Klass, Philip J.; Knight, Damon Francis, 1922-2002.; Kornbluth, C. M. (Cyril M.), 1923-1958.; Kubilius, Walter.; Kummer, Frederic Arnold, 1873-1943.; Kuttner, Henry.; Lafferty, R. A.; Laumer, Keith, 1925-1993.; Leiber, Fritz, 1910-1992.; Les Tina, Dorothy.; Ley, Willy, 1906-1969.; Long, Frank Belknap, 1901-1994.; Lowndes, Robert W.; Meredith, Scott.; Merril, Judith, 1923-1997.; Michel, John B., 1917-1968.; Moskowitz, Sam.; Niven, Larry.; Padgett, Lewis.; Panshin, Alexei, 1940-; Perl, Arnold.; Pohl, Frederick Julius, 1889-1991.; Pohl, Frederik.; Pratt, Fletcher, 1897-1956.; Rambelli, Roberta.; Reed, Kit.; Rothman, Milton A.; Samachson, Joseph, 1906-1980.; Schmitz, James H., 1911-1981.; Sheckley, Robert, 1928-2005.; Silverberg, Robert.; Simak, Clifford D., 1904-1988.; Smith, E. E. (Edward Elmer), 1890-1965.; Smith, George O. (George Oliver), 1911-1981.; Sturgeon, Theodore.; Thomas, Theodore L.; Vance, Jack, 1916-2013.; Van Vogt, A. E. (Alfred Elton), 1912-2000.; Wilson, Richard, 1920-1987.; Wollheim, Donald A.; Wyndham, John, 1903-1969.; Zelazny, Roger.; World Science Fiction Convention.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Editors -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Science fiction fans.; Science fiction, American.; Science fiction -- Societies, etc.; Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts.; Correspondence.; Fanzines.; Manuscripts for publication.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Programs (documents); Authors.; Editors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frederik Pohl Jr., 1965, 1967, 1969
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A, general, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Forrest J, 1936-1964; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Aldiss, Brian, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Poul, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1938-1964; 13 folders (Box 1)
  - B, general, 1937-1964 (Box 1)
  - Ballantine, Betty, 1953-1964; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Ballantine, Ian, 1951-1963; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Bester, Alfred, 1953-1963 (Box 2)
  - Bixby, Jerome, 1952-1964 (Box 2)
  - Blish, James, 1936-1964; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Blish, Virginia, 1949-1962 (Box 2)
  - Bok, Hannes, 1939-1950 (Box 2)
  - Boucher, Anthony, 1952-1955 (Box 2)
  - Bradbury, Ray, 1939-1964 (Box 2)
  - Brunner, John, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Budrys, A. J., 1953-1964 (Box 2)
  - Busby, F.M., 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - C, general, 1935-1962 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, John W., 1937-1948 (Box 2)
  - Carnell, Edward J., 1936-1964; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - D, General, 1951-1965 (Box 2)
  - Davidson, Avram, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - DeCamp, L. Sprague, 1939-1942; 1949-1963; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Del Rey, Lester, 1941-1961 (Box 3)
  - Dick, Philip K., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Dickson, Gordon R., 1963-1965 (Box 3)
  - Disch, Thomas M., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Doubleday & Company, 1949-1964; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - E, general, 1952-1964 (Box 3)
  - Ellison, Harlan, 1964 (Box 3)
  - F, general, 1945-1964 (Box 3)
  - Farmer, Philip Jose, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - G, general, 1951-1968 (Box 3)
  - Galouye, Daniel. F., 1961-1963 (Box 3)
  - Gillespie, Jack, 1938-1957 (Box 3)
  - Greenberg, Martin, 1948-1962 (Box 3)
  - H, general, 1950-1964 (Box 3)
  - Harris, John Beynon, 1950-1963; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Harrison, Harry, 1950-1964 (Box 4)
  - Heinlein, Leslyn, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Heinlein, Robert, 1939-1964; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Herbert, Frank, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Huxley, Aldous, 1954 (Box 4)
  - I-J, general, 1951-1964 (Box 4)
  - Jenkins, Will F., 1959-1963 (Box 4)
  - K, general, 1945-1963 (Box 4)
  - Kauffmann, Stanley, 1952-1957 (Box 4)
  - Klaas, Philip, 1947-1963; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Knight, Damon, 1941-1964; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Kornbluth, Cyril M., 1939-1964; 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Kubilius, Walter, 1936-1951 (Box 5)
  - Kummer, Fred, 1939-1951; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kuttner, Henry, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - Kyle, David A., 1936-1964 (Box 5)
  - L, general, 1945-1964 (Box 5)
  - LaCroix-Harcourt, Jacques, 1946-1955 (Box 5)
  - Lafferty, R.A., 1961-1964 (Box 5)
  - Laumer, Keith, 1961-1967 (Box 5)
  - Leiber, Fritz, 1948-1964; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - LesTina, Dorothy L., 1942-1943 May; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - LesTina, Dorothy L., 1943 Jun-1945 Aug; 13 folders (Box 6)
  - LesTina, Dorothy L., 1945 Sep-1961; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Ley, Willy, 1940-1964 (Box 7)
  - Long, Frank Belknap, 1939-1942 (Box 7)
  - Lowndes, Robert W., 1936-1960; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Lowndes, Robert W. ,to Rosalind Wylie, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Lyon, Herbert Allan, 1950-1955 (Box 7)
  - M, general, 1951-1964 (Box 7)
  - Mason, Bill and Evelyn, 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - Mason, Leslie and Dorothy, 1936-1948; 1959 (Box 7)
  - Meredith, Scott, 1951-1964 (Box 7)
  - Merril, Judith, 1947-1952; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Merril, Judith, 1953-1964; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Michel, John, 1936-1951 (Box 8)
  - Mills, Robert, 1951-1964 (Box 8)
  - Morrison, Henry, 1967-1964 (Box 8)
  - Moskowitz, Sam, 1937-1963 (Box 8)
  - N, general, 1950-1964 (Box 8)
  - Niven, Larry, 1964 (Box 8)
  - O, general, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - P, general, 1952-1964 (Box 8)
  - Panshin, Alexei, 1962-1964 (Box 8)
  - Perl, Arnold, 1955-1960 (Box 8)
  - Perri, Doe, 1938-1944; undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Playboy Magazine, 1959-1964 (Box 8)
  - Pohl, Anna Mason, 1941-1944; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Pohl, Frederick J. [no relation], 1960-1964 (Box 8)
  - Pohl, Frederik G., Sr., 1923-1955; 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Pohl children, 1956-1961 (Box 9)
  - Pohl family, miscellaneous, 1959; undated (Box 9)
  - Pohl relatives, 1959-1963 (Box 9)
  - Popular Science Publishing Co., 1946-1950 (Box 9)
  - Pratt, Fletcher, 1949-1953 (Box 9)
  - Q, general, 1963 (Box 9)
  - R, general, 1948-1964 (Box 9)
  - Rambelli, Roberta, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Reed, Kit, 1959-1963 (Box 9)
  - Rothman, Milton, 1936-1962; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Sa-Sc (Box 9)
  - Se-So (Box 9)
  - Sp-Sz (Box 9)
  - St. Clair, Margaret, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Samachson, Joseph, 1950-1957 (Box 9)
  - Schmitz, James, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Science Fiction League of America, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Sheckley, Robert, 1952-1962 (Box 9)
  - Shir-Cliff, Bernard W., 1952-1956 (Box 9)
  - Silverberg, Robert, 1960-1964 (Box 10)
  - Simak, Clifford, 1940-1961; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Smith, E.E. “Doc”, 1939-1964; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Smith, George O., 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Sturgeon, Theodore, 1950-1963 (Box 10)
  - T, general, 1953-1963 (Box 10)
  - Thomas, Theodore L., 1961-1964 (Box 10)
  - Tucker, Robert and Wilson, 1935-1943; 1949-1964; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - U, general, 1936-1967 (Box 10)
  - V, general, 1946-1967 (Box 10)
  - Vance, Jack, 1961-1964 (Box 10)
  - Van Vogt, A.E., 1961-1963 (Box 10)
  - W, general, 1948-1964 (Box 10)
  - Weiner, Norbert, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Williamson, Jack, 1939-1952; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Williamson, Jack, 1953-1964; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - W1lson, Richard, 1935-1964; 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Wollheim, Donald, 1936-1960; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Wylie, Dirk, 1934-1948; undated; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Wylie, Rosalind, 1939-1958 (Box 11)
  - Z, general, 1952-1964 (Box 11)
  - Zelazny, Roger, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Zissman, Merrll, 1951-1960 (Box 11)
  - Unidentified, 1947-1962; undated (Box 11)
- Legal and financial material
  - Business
    - General, 1939-1964; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Memoranda of agreement, contracts, 1945-1964; 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Personal
    - General, 1940-1958 (Box 12)
    - Legal, 1917-1961; 2 folders (Box 12)
- Writings
  - Asimov, Isaac
    - The Monkey's Fingers, 1951; typescript carbon, 13 pp. (Box 13)
    - Nobody There But..., undated; typescript carbon, 15 pp. (Box 13)
    - Space Ranger Original, 1951; typescript carbon, 11 pp. and fragments (Box 13)
    - Strange Playfellow, undated; typescript carbon, 22 pp. (Box 13)
  - Blish, James
    - Proposals for three titles, 1950; undated (Box 13)
  - Leiber, Fritz
    - Abstracts of two stories, 1951 (Box 13)
  - Pohl, Frederik G.
    - The Abominable Earthman, 1961; typescript carbon, 37 pp. (Box 13)
    - The Age of the Pussyfoot, circa 1965; typescript carbon and photocopy, 176 pp.; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - The Midas Plague (working title: The Blessed), undated; first draft, typescript, 68 pp.; first draft, typescript carbon, 68 pp. plus 5 pp. inserts; draft B, typescript carbon, 72 pp.; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - My Lady Green Sleeves, undated; first draft, typescript, 59 pp. (Box 13)
    - Three Portraits and a Prayer, 1961; annotated typescript, 21 pp. (Box 13)
    - Under Two Moons, 1965; annotated typescript, 50 pp. (Box 13)
  - Pohl, Frederik G., and C. M. Kornbluth
    - Critical Mass, 1961; annotated typescript, 51 pp. (Box 13)
  - Pratt, Fletcher
    - Outline for a series of articles, undated (Box 13)
  - Wylie, Dirk
    - Thralls of the Ice World, undated; novelette, outline (Box 13)
- Miscellanea
  - Advertising written and designed by Frederik G. Pohl
    - For Dirk Wylie and Outdoor Life magazine, undated (Box 13)
    - For Outdoor Life magazine and Foremost Books, undated (Box 13)
    - For Popular Science magazine (Box 13)
  - Clients file (Box 14)
  - Illustrations by Hannes Bok, printed material (Box 14)
  - Memorabilia
    - General (Box 14)
    - Photographs (Box 14)
  - Printed material (Box 14)
  - Magazine articles (Box 14)
  - Newspaper articles, 1945-1964; undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Proposals and scripts, Science Fiction Writers of America, undated (Box 14)
- Fanzines, conference material, other fan publications
  - Algol, 1965-1968; nos. 10, 14 (Box 15)
  - The amateur spectator, 1948; vol. 1, no. 4 (Box 15)
  - Amra, 1965-1968; vol. 2, nos. 35-46 (Box 15)
  - Appalling stories, 1966; no. 19 (Box 15)
  - The Argentine science fiction review, 1968; vol. 1, no. 6 (Box 15)
  - Auslander, 1965-1966; nos. 1-2 (Box 15)
  - Australian science fiction review, 1966-1967; nos. 3-9, 11, 13 (Box 15)
  - Barsoomian times, 1964-1965; nos. 3-6, 8 (Box 15)
  - Baycon (26th WorldCon), 1968; progress report (Box 15)
  - The B.E.C. pelican, 1964; vol. 1, no. 2 (Box 15)
  - Bibliographica futurica/fantastica, 1967; sample copy (Box 15)
  - Bjottings, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Bluedex, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Boskone, 1965-1969; annual meeting programs, miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Box 41, 1967; vol. 1, no. 1 (Box 15)
  - Carbo #9 (Carbonated), 1965; no. 11; also known as Ben-Crud-Yo #14 (Box 15)
  - Cinder, 1967; nos. 4-7 (Box 15)
  - Concentrate, 1968; no. 1 (Box 15)
  - Convention Annual, Chicon III edition (20th WorldCon), 1962; no. 2 (Box 15)
  - Convention Annual, Discon Edition (21st WorldCon), 1963; no. 3 (Box 15)
  - Criticism -- who needs it?, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Cry in the night, 1945; Opus 5, no. 1 (Box 16)
  - Dakkar, no. 1 (Box 16)
  - Dallascon bulletin, 1969; nos. 1-2 (Box 16)
  - David Malone's science fiction magazine, 1968; no. 1 (Box 16)
  - December 27, 1968, only issue (Box 16)
  - Degler, 1966-1967; nos, 157-159, 164, 168-179, 181 (Box 16)
  - Delve 4, 1965; vol. 1, no. 4; also known as Ben-Crud-Yo #15 (Box 16)
  - Detention, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Different, 1968; vol. 3, no. 3 (Box 16)
  - Discord, 1962; no. 16 (Box 16)
  - Epilogue, 1964; vol. 1, no. 3 (Box 16)
  - ERB-dom, 1964-1967; nos. 11-18, 21 (Box 16)
  - Extrapolation, 1959-1966; vol. 1, no. 1/2 through vol. 7, no. 1/2 (Box 16)
  - Eye, 1967; no. 21 (Box 16)
  - F&SF Book Company, 1959-1969; nos. 49, 71, 75-79, 81-84, 86, 88-90, 93-96 (Box 16)
  - Fanac, S.T.F. (Box 16)
  - Fan's world of fantasy, 1967; vol. 7, nos. 1, 3 (Box 16)
  - Fantastic universe, 1966; supplement no. 1, parts 1 and 2 (Box 16)
  - Fantasy-comics, 1966; vol. 3, nos. 4-5 (Box 17)
  - First draft, 1967-1968; nos. 185, 187-188, 193-194, 198-201 (Box 17)
  - Fanzine advisor, 1969 (Box 17)
  - First Fandom magazine, 1967-1968; nos. 13-15 (Box 17)
  - Focal point, undated; no. 23 (Box 17)
  - Forecast 1965, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Forgotten sea of Mars, 1965 (Box 17)
  - Forry, 1966 (Box 17)
  - Future unbounded, 1968; progress report no. 1 (Box 17)
  - Galactic outpost, 1964-1965; nos. 1, 3 (Box 17)
  - Grommish, undated; no. 1 (Box 17)
  - General catalogue no. 52, undated; nos. 52-53 (Box 17)
  - Habakkuk, 1966-1967; Chapter 2, Verses 1-3 (Box 17)
  - How to win games and influence destiny, 1968 (Box 17)
  - How we won, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Hugo report, 1967; nos. 1-2 (Box 17)
  - The humanist, 1957; vol. 17, no. 6 (Box 17)
  - Hyborian times, 1967; no. 1 (Box 17)
  - Hydronical, 1967; no. 1 (Box 17)
  - If, 1952-1964; author index, covering vol. 1 no. 1 through vol. 14, no. 4 (Box 17)
  - Index to Arkham House, 1965; no. 1 (Box 17)
  - Infinite Fanac, 1967; nos. 8-9 (Box 17)
  - Info journal, 1967; vol. 1, no. 1 (Box 17)
  - Interplanetary Exploration Society, 1958; first meeting (Box 17)
  - International science fantasy art exhibition bulletin, 1968; no. 3 (Box 17)
  - Introduction to Eckankar, 1966 (Box 17)
  - It takes a pretty powerful fan to beat the draft, 1954 (Box 17)
  - LeJardin sideral, 1964-1965; nos. 17/18 and 19/20 (Box 17)
  - Journal of the Australian Science Fiction Association, 1968; vol. 1, no. 7 (Box 17)
  - Kaleidoscope Books, undated (Box 17)
  - Kaleidoscope 65, 1965 (Box 17)
  - Kallikanzaros, 1968; no. 4 (Box 17)
  - The life and legend of Hannes Bok, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Lighthouse, 1964-1966; nos. 11-14 (Box 18)
  - Locus, 1968; trial issue no. 2 (Box 18)
  - Lore, 1965-1966; vol. 1, nos. 2, 3, 4, 7 (Box 18)
  - Luna monthly, 1969; no. 1 (Box 18)
  - Luna comix, 1965; no. 1; also known as Ben-Crud-Yo #119, Wanderer #10, and Sue Jackson #6 (Box 18)
  - Lunacon, 1965; 1967,; 1969; annual meeting reports (Box 18)
  - Lunatique, 1967 (Box 18)
  - The man by Von, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Maneki-Neko, 1967; no. 1 (Box 18)
  - Marcon III, 1968; annual meeting report (Box 18)
  - The Martian Hern, 1966; no. 4 (Box 18)
  - MegCon Report, 1962; no. 57 (Box 18)
  - Meicon, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Mensa science fiction (Box 18)
  - Metrofan, 1958; meeting of the New York Fandom Council, nos. 8-9 (Box 18)
  - Midwestcon, 1965; 1969; annual meeting reports (Box 18)
  - Minicon, [1968?]; progress report nos. 1-2 (Box 18)
  - Mirage, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Monda kulturo, 1964; no. 9 (Box 18)
  - Moonweb, 1966; vol. 1, no. 1 (Box 18)
  - Munich roundup, 1968-1969; nos. 104-105 (Box 18)
  - The multi-man, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Mystification, 1966; vol. 1, no. 3; vol. 2, no. 1 (Box 18)
  - National fantasy fan, 1966-1969; vol. 25, nos. 4-6; vol. 26, nos. 1-7, vol. 27, nos. 1-6, vol. 28, nos. 5-6, vol. 29, no. 1; miscellaneous pieces (Box 18)
  - News release, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Nebula Awards, miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - New York '67, 1967; annual meeting miscellany (Box 18)
  - Niekas, 1964-1965; nos. 10-13 (Box 18)
  - New England Mensa, 1967 (Box 19)
  - Nyarlathotep, 1966-1968; nos. 4, 6 (Box 19)
  - NyCon (25th WorldCon), 1967; annual meeting (Box 19)
  - Nycon comics, 1967; nos. 3-5 (Box 19)
  - Odd, 1966-1967; nos. 14, 16, 18 (Box 19)
  - on and on and on, etc. (Box 19)
  - Oof, 1968; nos. 9-1/2, 10 (Box 19)
  - The original science fiction stories, 1963; vol. 11, no. 4 (Box 19)
  - Os, 1968; no. 1 (Box 19)
  - Ozarkon 2 (Box 19)
  - Pacificon 2 (22nd WorldCon), 1964; miscellaneous (Box 19)
  - Paranoia and science fiction, 1967 (Box 19)
  - The Pavlat report, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Penman, 1965; vol. 2, no. 2 (Box 19)
  - Perihelion, 1967-1969; nos. 3, 4, 6 (Box 19)
  - Pet rich, 1965; no. 4, also known as Ben-Crud-Yo #18, Wanderer #9, Sue Jackson #5, and Beth Robinson #32; no. 5, also known as Ben-Crud-Yo #20, Wanderer #11, and Sue Jackson #7 (Box 19)
  - The proceedings: ChiCon III (20th WorldCon), 1962-1963 (Box 19)
  - The proper Boskonian, 1967-1969; vol. 1, nos. 0, 1, 3, 4 (Box 19)
  - Psychotic, 1965-1968; nos. 18, 22-25 (Box 19)
  - The pulp era, 1967; no. 66 (Box 19)
  - QRM, 1967; no. 1 (Box 19)
  - RCD-25, 1967; Ron Cobb drawings (Box 20)
  - Riverside quarterly, 1964-1969; vol. 1, nos. 1-4; vol. 2, nos. 1-4; vol. 3, no. 4 (Box 20)
  - Renaissance, 1969; vol. 1, nos. 1-2 (Box 20)
  - St. Louiscon (27th WorldCon), 1969; miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Science fiction bulletin, 1966-1967; vol. 1, nos. 1-3 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction critic, 1967; nos. 3, 4, 6, 7 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction hall of fame, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction news, 1958; no. 23 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction opinion, 1967; undated; nos. 1, 7 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction review [San Diego], 1964-1966; nos. 26, 37-38, 40-43 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction review [Santa Monica], 1968-1969; nos. 28-30 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction times [Berlin], 1967-1969; nos. 73, 75-83, 87-88, 91 (Box 20)
  - Science fiction times [Syracuse], 1958-1969; nos. 187 (vol. 13), 273 (vol. 12), 280, 283-284, 303-304, 420, 420a, 421-424, 426-434, 438-441, 443, 445, 447-455, 460-465, 2 issues without number or date (Box 20)